nutritionfacts.org 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy | NutritionFacts.org

NutritionFacts.org has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy and security of the users of this website. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy, and how we treat Non-Personally and Personally Identifiable Information collected from our visitors and users.

### What this Privacy Statement Covers

This privacy statement covers NutritionFacts.org’s treatment of Non-Personally Identifiable Information and Personally Identifiable Information collected by NutritionFacts.org through this website.

This privacy statement does not apply to the practices of companies that NutritionFacts.org does not own or control, or of persons that NutritionFacts.org does not employ or manage, including any third-party content contributors bound by contract and any third-party websites to which this website links. 

##### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We also collect and use information about your interactions with the website in a manner and format that does not identify you as an individual (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”). We may collect, use, and disclose Non-Personally Identifiable Information as set forth below.

**Cookies Information**

Like many websites, when you visit NutritionFacts.org, we may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets NutritionFacts.org help you log in and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey information to us about how you use the website (e.g., the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take), and allow us to track your usage of the website over time. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the website may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**Clear Gifs/Web Beacons Information**

When you use the website, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails and correspondence sent to our users to track which emails are opened and which links are clicked by recipients. The information is allows for more accurate reporting and improvement of the website.

**Log File Information**

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you use our website, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include anonymous information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the website, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

**Analytics**

We use third-party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for NutritionFacts.org. These tools collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including the web pages you visit, your browser add-ons, your browser’s width and height, and other information that assists us in improving NutritionFacts.org. We collect and use this analytics information in aggregate form such that it cannot reasonably be manipulated to identify any particular individual user

##### Personally Identifiable Information

We collect information that can be used to identify you as an individual (“Personally Identifiable Information”) only when you provide such information directly to us in connection with using the website. We ask for Personally Identifiable Information such as your name and e-mail address when you register for a NutritionFacts.org account or if you correspond with us (in which case we will also retain our responses). We may also retain any messages you send through NutritionFacts.org and its services. We also collect and retain Personally Identifiable Information such as first name, last name, address, and donation preferences when you donate through our website. We may receive Personally Identifiable Information about you from third parties, including, for example, information about your use of certain applications. For example, if you access our website through a third-party connection or log-in, for example, through Facebook Connect, by “following,” “liking,” linking your account to the NutritionFacts.org, etc., that third party may pass certain information about your use of its service to us. This information could include, but is not limited to, the user ID associated with your account, any information you have permitted the third party to share with us, and any information you have made public in connection with that service. You should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to NutritionFacts.org.

##### Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We may use and disclose your Personally Identifiable Information only as follows:

  * To support and improve our website offerings.
  * To inquire about donation-related transactions and activities. This includes sending you emails, receipts, notices of payment frequency changes, and alerting you if we need a different credit card number. We use third parties for secure credit card transaction processing, and we send billing information to those third parties to process your credit card payments. We do not store credit card details related to your account directly on our servers.
  * To send you website updates. For example, we may let you know about temporary or permanent changes to our website, new features, updates, and changes to our Privacy Policy.
  * To provide customer support.
  * To protect the rights and safety of our users and third parties, as well as our own.
  * To meet legal requirements like complying with court orders and valid subpoenas.
  * To provide information to representatives and advisors, like attorneys and accountants, to help us comply with legal, accounting, or security requirements.
  * To prosecute and defend a court, arbitration, or similar proceeding.
  * To communicate with you about your account for informational, not promotional, reasons.
  * To send you informational and promotional content that you may choose (or “opt-in”) to receive, such as daily, weekly, and monthly emails. You can stop receiving our promotional emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in every email.

##### Public Information and Third Parties

**Blog and Blog Commenting**

We have a public blog and commenting system on NutritionFacts.org. Any information you include in a comment on our blog may be read, collected, and used by anyone. If your Personal Information appears on our blog and you’d like it to be removed, contact us [here](https://nutritionfacts.org/contact). If we’re not able to remove your information, we’ll let you know why.

**Social Media Widgets**

NutritionFacts.org includes social media features, like the Facebook Like button, as well as other social media services. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

**Links to Third-Party Sites and Resources**

NutritionFacts.org includes numerous links to other websites, whose privacy practices may be different from our own. If you submit Personally Identifiable Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Website you visit.

##### Service Providers

If it is necessary to provide you a service you’ve requested, like send you a DVD, then we may provide your personal information to a service provider. We will restrict any service provider’s use of your personal information. We will tell you whenever reasonably possible and you may request at any time the name of our service providers.

##### Instances where we are required to share your Personally Identifiable Information

NutritionFacts.org will disclose Personal Information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our website; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of NutritionFacts.org, our Users or others.

NutritionFacts.org recognizes the following guiding principles for any required sharing of information to third parties: a) freedom of expression and identity choice are core to the and should be respected as such, b) law enforcement requests must comply with all laws, particularly those protecting user information, and must clearly establish the legal need for disclosure, c) law enforcement requests must be related to specific investigations and specific accounts implicated in those investigations, d) whenever legally permitted, and barring exceptional circumstances where safety or other factors are deemed a reasonable counteracting concern, Users should receive notice that their specific information is being requested with opportunity to inquire further or contest such requests.

##### Security

NutritionFacts.org is concerned with safeguarding your information. NutritionFacts.org uses commercially reasonable safeguards, such as the latest security practices and firewalling, to preserve the integrity and security of all information collected through the website. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from NutritionFacts.org, at all times. 

### Consent

If you do not consent to the collection, use or disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information as outlined in this statement, please do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to NutritionFacts.org. If you have provided Personally Identifiable Information to NutritionFacts.org and no longer consent to its use or disclosure as outlined herein, please notify NutritionFacts.org at [privacy@NutritionFacts.org](mailto:privacy@nutritionfacts.org).

##### Changing or Deleting Your Information & Targeting Opt-Out

All registered users may review, update or correct the Personally Identifiable Information provided in their registration or account profile by changing or updating their Profile in their account. If you choose to opt-out entirely, then your account may become deactivated and you will need to re-register should you decide to opt-in again. To delete your account entirely, please [Contact Us](https://nutritionfacts.org/contact). However, you understand and agree that we are not able to remove your Personally Identifiable Information from the records of any third party who has been provided with your information in compliance with the use and sharing policy outlined above.

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

NutritionFacts.org may at any time, without notice to you and in its sole discretion, amend this statement from time to time. Please review this statement periodically. Your continued use of the NutritionFacts.org website after any such amendments signifies your acceptance thereof. 

### Questions or Suggestions

If you have questions about this privacy statement, or your own Personally Identifiable Information, please e-mail us at [privacy@nutritionfacts.org](mailto:privacy@nutritionfacts.org).

* * *

Last Modified: August 30th 2017
